[Music] today on Polar Ice creamy
we are going to make white chocolate
Blondie ice cream this is going to be
amazing so let's see what we need to
So yeah this flavor is inspired by gelato
messina and scientifically sweet website,
I follow her on Instagram and she flashed up
a recipe for what she calls white chocolate
brownies but they're what I know as blondies the
difference between Blondie and brownie is brownie
uses cocoa powder and chocolate with white sugar
and blondies use white chocolate with brown sugar
and vanilla uh everything else pretty much is
the same so we're going to make the blondies
whil they're baking and getting ready we'll
then do the ice cream and then we'll come back
and combine everything with a nice secret swirl
for the end so first thing we need to do get the
oven on I'm following scientifically sweet recipe
here in front of me so you're going to see me keep
looking backwards and forwards not my recipe don't
know it so preheat the oven to 350 we've also got
an 8x8 pan W an 8 by8 pan we're going to line that
right with our pan lined with baking parchment we
can measure things out we need two bowls and
we are going to in this small bowl we're going
to weigh out our white chocolate and and our
butter so what do we need we need 85 G of white
chocolate there we go 85 G of white chocolate and
100 G of butter you can melt this over a bamy you
can melt it however however you like I'm going
to melt it in the microwave just be careful in
the microwave so you don't burn anything right
so it took about a minute something like that
just um I I did a 30 30C blast and then a couple
of shorter blasts once the Butter's melted start
stirring in that white chocolate you don't want
a white chocolate to burn it burns really easily
and then it's ruined but now our white chocolate
is just finally doing that last stage of melting
in the hot butter so it's perfect super smooth
white chocolate and butter mix now in here we're
going to add in everything apart from the flour
so let's start with our sugar which is 135 G 55
G of light brown sugar I don't have that I
have demera sugar so go brown sugar eggs and
salt all right eggs two room temperature eggs
and salt we're using pink salt how much salt
half a teaspoon there we go half a teaspoon
of salt and we need to mix this I don't have
an electric hand mixer so I'm going to do it
by hand it says mix till it's pale and thick
so pale and thick add in the vanilla how much
vanilla 1 and 1/2 teaspoon 7 mlit random that is
three tiny teaspoons for me cuz I like vanilla
bean paste
flavor not sure that would be
enough otherwise so in that flavor
goes you can put in as much vanilla flavor
as you like because it doesn't really have
a negative impact on the recipe cuz it's
vanilla being paste rather than alcohol
in vanilla extract next we need to
mix in our melted butter and white
chocolate like this is I'm doing this in
real time [Music] so so let's mix this
in I'm using mostly valona white chocolate there's
also some uh white chocolate chips from Walmart
nice finally we need to add in the flour so
says fold it in 160 G worth of allpurpose
flour we're not whisking this flour in
we are just folding it in until it's
Incorporated all right that's that's it
all we need to do now is to fold in some
more white chocolate chips
Safeway Safeway Zone and get it in
here that tastes delicious right this needs to
go in the oven for 25 to 30 minutes so let's
do that quick tidy up onto the ice cream whilst
they're baking quick tidy up took me 3 minutes so
white chocolate ice cream going to start
off with 680 this is a 1.5 L batch so
that's three ninja creamy batches two ninja
creamy Deluxe batches one 1 lit batch plus
a ninja creamy one 1500 G batch however
you want to break it down 680 G of milk
and into that adding 440 G of 33% whipping
cream nice we're going to use a stabilizer
some people say why do you use stabilizer
some and not in others some recipes do
better with a stabilizer than others mint does
better with a stabilizer white chocolate does
better with a stabilizer 100 g of sugar
better put it on the scale e that would
help 100 g of sugar today we're going to
use dextrose and that is 100 G of dextrose
100 G of dextrose and into that we're
going to add in our milk powder which is 55
G and our stabilizer what are we
going to use this time I'm going
to use my own blend this is an old
special ingredients tub that I have
repurposed um I'm going to use 1.8 G of
stabilizer white chocolate has this habit of
being super cold when you make it into
ice cream so always recommend a little
bit more stabilizer if you don't
use stabilizer you'll never know
that is up to you so we're just going
to mix all that together 110 G of white
chocolate random little things in there
110 gram just going to break these in half
nice that is everything
now we're going to add our dry ingredients
into our wet ingredients and let's get
that on the hob and warm it up to 85c
185f nice simple stir bring it up to
temperature and then take it off the heat nothing
crazy temperature 85c 185 f some am of Interest
some people ask me about evaporation and I don't
talk about it that often but when you cook a base
by adding the skin milk powder and by evaporating
some of the water off you actually are emanating
the pasteurizing process done in a commercial
environment that's why it's done that's why we
do it it reduces the water content gives you a
more luxurious base add that with the stabilizer
you got this amazing kind of combination what
we got we got 2 minutes left on our blondies w
chocolate brownies whatever so let's just see we
started off with 1.5 kilos 1500 G there we go we
got uh 1.5% evaporation rate on there so not too
bad I'd say if you really want to balance properly
using an ice cream calculator and this will this
won't work on dream Scoops or the more simplified
calculators if you use Patrick's ice cream
calculator you can balance against evaporation
rate so you could evaporate more off up to 5%
balance your recipe to that point if you put zero
evaporation which can't happen if you heat your
base that's what the steam is it's water so you
are evaporating water if you try and balance your
recipe at 0% evaporation then you evaporate water
off of it your numbers will be wrong all right
so when you're deep in the science of ice cream
there's a lot of things to to consider that's one
of them if you don't use an ice calculator and you
follow my recipes then just don't worry about
it and we're going to put a good whatever this
Spoonful size is what is that half a tablespoon
we're going to do 3/4 of a tablespoon of vanilla
bean paste not vanilla extract because of the
alcohol vanilla bean paste oh yeah white chocolate
is always pretty much flavored with vanilla or
vanillin um which is the chemical compound flavor
for vanilla um but there we go let's pop this
in the fridge it's super early in the morning
it's Hub us 9 so we can get this chilled down and
churned and loaded up before the end of the day
[Music]
does your oven make that stupid ass noise right
let's get these out the oven give you a shot of
what these look like smooth top we're going
to steam the camera up in a minute just SL
toasting around the outside yes looking good now
all we need to do is cool these if I lift that out
yeah that's going to go everywhere so let's
do our best at getting these out of the pan
like that we're going to cut them up and put
them in ice cream anyway so it doesn't really
matter but now you can see how delicious
these look I'm going to tidy up the kitchen
let everything cool down ice cream base as
well and then we'll come and churn and load
it all up I rapidly chilled my ice cream base
down it's just finishing off in the fridge now
we're going to cut up our Blondie uh keep
some aside and we are going to store some
in the freezer for another time going to use
the Viva chamber vacuum machine let's cut our
Blondie up so we're going to put some in the
container yes I've eaten the corner [Music]
right so our Blondie is [Music] here can't
stop eating this I'm going to put that
aside for storing for vacuum sealing put it in the
freezer so let's get our ice cream base in machine
and get that churning white chocolate ice cream
is notorious for the cocoa butter solidifying
on top if that happens to you all you got to
do is reincorporate it you can do this with a
whisk you can do this with an immersion blender
whatever you have to hand mine hasn't done it
[Music]
and the final thing is we're
going to take our worther soft
caramels how many are we going to
take more than that 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16
20 going to unwrap all of these and put them in
this little jug we're going to turn this into a
caramel sauce so we're going to add some
cream into this free solid whilst that's
doing let's put this in the microwave and melt
all down all right 30 seconds and then another
20 25 seconds Got Us close now we're going
to try and mix This Together there we go
it goes together relatively easy it's obviously
boiling hot we can just pop this in the
refrigerator for the remaining time making sure
not to absolutely decimate the glass shelf in the
refrigerator so see you in about 10 minutes right
we're coming up to the last few minutes of churing
I want to get a couple of these pieces the center
pieces so the soft pieces without a harder Edge
into the ice cream base I want those to break up
and distribute around the ice cream let's gently
drizzle just a little bit of this into here like
that I'm going to put some more of this in there
[Music]
this caramel is perfect let's get some dished up
okay first things first this camel was perfect
so so good it's been in the fridge for hours
and hours and hours all day not gone hard
just oh literally could eat that whole thing
and it's Friday so I might uh onto the ice cream
beautiful scooping texture perfect amount of over
run smells delicious I can see big old
pieces of Blondie in [Music] there I'm
shaking my head at how freaking good this is
some days I just surprise even myself in how
good some of these ice creams actually are
the ice cream is a perfect combination of
white chocolate flavor and vanilla vanilla
is the predominant flavor you're tasting in
white chocolate anyway the blondies or white
brownies as scientifically sweet call them
they're incredible things the texture is perfect
Frozen in the ice cream the outside piece if
you're an outside brownie person the outside
edge is still crispy and lovely the inside
is still super chewy and decadent the flavor
of those blondies is incredible good quality
chocolate make sure you use that overall this
combination is perfect with the worther caramel
top it's so easy just to add cream to those
in the microwave leave it in a fridge for
hours and on until you're ready to use it
like I said this is It's F it's Friday and
I've got a huge batch of this that I can
Now consume Blown Away by how good this
one is you got to try this yes there's a few
ingredients to making this but my word is it
good don't forget to like And subscribe
I'll catch you on the next one [Music]